=A Puppetry=
= دمية =
=Episode 5=
= الحلقة 5 =
I'm hungry.
أنا جائع.
(She's not reacting to it properly.)
(إنها لا تتفاعل معها بشكل صحيح.)
(How can this be?)
(كيف يمكن أن يكون هذا؟)
You
أنت
are full?
انه ممتلئ؟
Yes.
نعم.
(What an odd person.)
(يا له من شخص غريب.)
You're a musician?
هل أنت موسيقي؟
Yes.
نعم.
You came to us because of our reputation?
أتيت إلينا بسبب سمعتنا؟
You want to be famous?
تريد أن تكون مشهوراً؟
Good.
نعم.
I can make you
انا استطيع صنعك
one of the best musicians in the world.
أحد أفضل الموسيقيين في العالم.
(She is very...)
(هي في غاية...)
(Calm and composed.)
(هادئ ومكون.)
What?
ماذا؟
Is there a problem?
هل هناك مشكلة؟
Are you not sad?
الا انت حزين
They never believed in me.
لم يؤمنوا بي قط.
And now,
و الأن،
I'll prove it myself
سأثبت ذلك بنفسي
that I am capable
أنني قادر
of continuing Chen Theater Troupe's legacy.
لمواصلة إرث فرقة مسرح تشن.
Mai Prefecture's
محافظة ماي
Annual Puppetry Festival
مهرجان العرائس السنوي
will take place soon.
قريبا.
All reputable troupes
جميع الفرق ذات السمعة الطيبة
will come here.
سيأتي هنا.
I will make myself known
سأعرف نفسي
during then.
خلال ذلك الوقت.
(She's not devastated at all.)
(إنها ليست محطمة على الإطلاق).
(Does she have PTSD?)
(هل لديها اضطراب ما بعد الصدمة؟)
(I will revitalize Chen Theater Troupe)
(سأحيي فرقة مسرح تشين)
(and immortalize its legacy.)
(وخلد إرثه.)
(Chen Residence)
(سكن تشين)
(After just one night,)
(بعد ليلة واحدة فقط)
(the Chen Theater Troupe turned into a desolate sight.)
(تحولت فرقة مسرح تشين إلى مشهد مقفر).
That's my seniors' rooms.
هذه غرف كبار السن لدي.
Just sleep at any one of them.
فقط نم عند أي واحد منهم.
I'm tired now.
انا متعب الان.
I'll go to bed.
أنا سوف أذهب إلى السرير.
Wait.
انتظر.
What should we do next?
ماذا علينا أن نفعل بعد ذلك؟
(Master, seniors...)
(ماجستير ، كبار السن ...)
(If I knew this would happen,)
(إذا علمت أن هذا سيحدث ،)
(I would rather stay)
(أفضل البقاء)
(in that doomed cycle.)
(في تلك الدورة المنكوبة).
(Plot development...)
(تطوير قطعة الأرض ...)
(Encounter)
(يواجه .. ينجز)
(Rescued)
(منقذ)
(So I have to follow the plot development)
(لذلك علي أن أتابع تطور الحبكة)
(and advance the story)
(ودفع القصة)
(before I'm able to return to my world?)
(قبل أن أتمكن من العودة إلى عالمي؟)
(The hints for further development are here.)
(تلميحات لمزيد من التطوير هنا.)
(It seems like the plot is well under way.)
(يبدو أن الحبكة تسير على قدم وساق).
Song Keyang.
سونغ كيانغ.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
The puppets were all burned.
تم حرق جميع الدمى.
We need new ones.
نحن بحاجة جديدة.
You want to make new ones?
تريد أن تصنع أشياء جديدة؟
Yes.
نعم.
In this fine weather,
في هذا الطقس الجيد ،
we should work hard.
يجب أن نعمل بجد.
Besides,
بجانب،
you said you wanted
قلت أنك تريد
to take part in the competition.
للمشاركة في المسابقة.
And now?
و الأن؟
You give me a lot of excuses.
أنت تعطيني الكثير من الأعذار.
When did I give you any excuses?
متى أعطيتك أي أعذار؟
Start working then.
ابدأ العمل بعد ذلك.
All talk
كل الكلام
and no trousers.
ولا سراويل.
It's just making puppets.
إنها مجرد دمى.
Do you need to yell at me?
هل تريد الصراخ في وجهي؟
♪To commemorate the past, the people raise their glass♪
لإحياء ذكرى الماضي ، يرفع الناس زجاجهم
♪The inebriation has caught up but the blissful moment still hasn't come♪
لقد حدث السكر لكن اللحظة السعيدة لم تأت بعد ♪
♪The twigs of the mimosa tree fold under the weather♪
تطوى أغصان شجرة الميموزا تحت الطقس ♪
♪The heavy rain rinses the plain color stage on a quaint little town♪
يشطف المطر الغزير مرحلة اللون العادي في بلدة صغيرة جذابة ♪
♪A steed can't chase after the rouge and the perfume♪
♪ لا يمكن للفرس أن يلاحق الشفتين والعطر ♪
Get up.
استيقظ.
I'll do it.
سأفعل ذلك.
♪Stuck in forlornness, who can rescue me?♪
♪ عالق في اليأس ، من ينقذني؟
♪I can still remember how beautiful the thimbleberry bloomed♪
♪ ما زلت أتذكر كم هي جميلة أزهر ثيمبلبيري ♪
♪Time passed by but I can never forget the look in your eyes♪
♪ مر الوقت ولكني لا أستطيع أن أنسى النظرة في عينيك
(Chen Residence)
(سكن تشين)
♪If dreams can prolong our encounter♪
إذا كانت الأحلام يمكن أن تطيل لقائنا ♪
♪Can I drink with you again?♪
♪ هل أستطيع أن أشرب معك مرة أخرى؟
♪As I see the blooming and passing of the thimbleberry♪
كما أرى تفتح وتوت العليق ♪
♪When will we meet again after this separation?♪
متى نلتقي مرة أخرى بعد هذا الفراق؟
♪The language of flowers cannot answer the questions my heart poses♪
لغة الزهور لا تجيب على الأسئلة التي يطرحها قلبي
Liu Xiaoxiao.
ليو شياوكسياو.
You're wasting your time again.
أنت تضيع وقتك مرة أخرى.
We are running out of time.
الوقت يداهمنا.
Come out now and rehearse.
تعال الآن وتمرّن.
Do you hear me?
هل تسمعني؟
Liu Xiaoxiao.
ليو شياوكسياو.
I...
أنا...
The puppet you made
الدمية التي صنعتها
has wonky internal machinery.
لديها آلية داخلية متزعزعة.
How am I supposed to rehearse with that?
كيف يفترض بي أن أتدرب على ذلك؟
- Besides... - Besides,
- إلى جانب ... - إلى جانب ذلك ،
we need to rent a stall.
نحن بحاجة لاستئجار كشك.
Is that right?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Yes.
نعم.
And many stages...
ومراحل عديدة ...
Have been rented out.
تم تأجيرها.
I know what's on your mind.
أنا أعرف ما يدور في ذهنك.
Yes,
نعم،
there aren't a lot of stalls available.
لا يوجد الكثير من الأكشاك المتاحة.
There are many troupes here
هناك فرق كثيرة هنا
so they increased the price
فرفعوا السعر
for the so-called hunger marketing.
لما يسمى بتسويق الجوع.
It's normal that the stages are in high demand.
من الطبيعي أن يكون الطلب على المراحل مرتفعًا.
What are you talking about?
ما الذي تتحدث عنه؟
We don't have a stage. You just need to know this.
ليس لدينا مرحلة.  أنت فقط بحاجة إلى معرفة هذا.
(Stage: Place where a play is performed) If there's no solution to it,
(المرحلة: المكان الذي تؤدى فيه المسرحية) إذا لم يكن هناك حل لها ،
forget about everything then.
نسيان كل شيء بعد ذلك.
I have a solution.
لدي حل.
(Our priority now)
(أولويتنا الآن)
(is to fix the puppets)
(هو إصلاح الدمى)
(then get a stage.)
(ثم ​​احصل على خشبة المسرح).
Troupe Leader Sun.
قائد الفرقة صن.
Your reputation precedes you.
سمعتك تسبقك.
They say you make the best
يقولون أنك تصنع الأفضل
rod puppets.
دمى قضيب.
We are apprentices from the Chen Theater Troupe
نحن متدربون من فرقة مسرح تشين
and we need
ونحن بحاجة
your service.
خدماتك.
You
أنت
should
ينبغي
go find someone else.
اذهب وابحث عن شخص آخر.
Troupe Leader Sun.
قائد الفرقة صن.
People came to me
جاء الناس إلي
for my service
لخدمتي
but none of them
لكن لا أحد منهم
truly loves puppetry.
حقا يحب الدمى.
Indeed.
في الواقع.
Sir.
سيد.
I love puppetry.
انا احب الدمى.
You claim to be an apprentice from the Chen Theater Troupe?
هل تدعي أنك متدرب من فرقة مسرح تشين؟
Yes.
نعم.
You know how to apply makeup to a puppet, don't you?
أنت تعرف كيف تضع المكياج على دمية ، أليس كذلك؟
Help me
ساعدني
make her look pretty.
اجعلها تبدو جميلة.
♪The tree's shadow sways with the breeze♪
ظل الشجرة يتأرجح مع النسيم
♪In a night, the fallen petals adorn the floor♪
♪ في الليل ، تتساقط البتلات لتزين الأرض
(The serious Liu Xiaoxiao)
(ليو شياو شياو الجاد)
(actually looks quite cute.)
(في الواقع يبدو لطيفًا جدًا.)
♪Playing my zither delicately, who is listening?♪
♪ عزف آلة آلة القانون خاصتي بدقة ، من الذي يستمع؟
♪Humming softly, who can I confide in?♪
♪ أزيز بصوت منخفض ، فمن يمكنني أن أثق به؟
Done.
فعله.
Look.
نظرة.
♪The past and the present, the day and night♪
الماضي والحاضر ، النهار والليل
You sure have potential.
بالتأكيد لديك إمكانات.
Thanks, sir.
شكرا سيدي.
What do you want me to do?
ماذا تريدني ان افعل؟
Just let me know.
فقط دعني اعرف.
We have the puppets now.
لدينا الدمى الآن.
We should celebrate it.
يجب أن نحتفل به.
Try this.
جرب هذا.
It's delicious.
إنه لذيذ.
Excuse me.
اعذرني.
Another portion, please.
جزء آخر من فضلك.
You still want more?
هل مازلت تريد المزيد؟
We already ordered a lot.
لقد طلبنا الكثير بالفعل.
Why? This is too expensive for you?
لماذا ا؟  هذا مكلف جدا بالنسبة لك؟
Eat.
تأكل.
(Did you hear?)
(هل سمعتي؟)
(The Chen Theater Troupe died in a fire.)
(ماتت فرقة مسرح تشين في حريق).
(Because)
(لان)
(of them,)
(منهم،)
(we had a hard time)
(لقد مررنا بوقت عصيب)
(establishing ourselves.)
(نؤسس أنفسنا).
(Now, good riddance.)
(الآن ، بئس المصير).
(They are all dead.)
(كلهم ماتوا).
(Now, it's our time to shine.)
(الآن ، حان وقت التألق.)
(Let's have a toast.)
(دعونا لها نخب.)
♪The dusk outside the window is spreading♪
♪ الغسق خارج النافذة ينتشر
♪The lanterns light up with anticipation♪
الفوانيس تضيء بترقب
♪The sea of lights illuminates the entire theater♪
♪ بحر الأضواء ينير المسرح بأكمله
♪The galaxy sprawls across the sky♪
المجرة تمتد عبر السماء ♪
♪The moon shows itself♪
القمر يظهر نفسه ♪
♪Gazing at the myriad lives♪
التحديق في حياة لا تعد ولا تحصى ♪
♪The bell chimes and the lady dances♪
يدق الجرس والسيدة ترقص
♪Her movements are mysterious and graceful♪
حركاتها غامضة ورشيقة ♪
♪A woman can solicit cheers and applause too♪
♪ يمكن للمرأة أن تلتمس الهتافات والتصفيق أيضًا ♪
♪Chatters fill the well-lit hall♪
♪ الدردشة تملأ القاعة المضاءة جيدًا
♪Holding a red candle by the stage♪
♪ عقد شمعة حمراء على خشبة المسرح ♪
♪Witnessing the blooming and wilting, oh, the freedom♪
مشاهدة التفتح والذبول يا الحرية
♪The theater welcomes you♪
المسرح يرحب بك ♪